Cool, so we've got it
so that our player looks
really good while they're running through
the scene, but we do have another weird
thing where it's pretty
awkward that they're
still running while they're jumping, unless
you're in like an action movie, that's not
really something that
people usually do, so
we're going to do some things to the jumping
animation to really make it look real.
In fact, we're actually
going to use our
player controller script
to be able to do that.
So if we go to our assets
and we can just close
off the source files,
collapse them because
it opened it up when we opened the animation
controller, and now if we open our player
controller script, now
in our player controller
script, we're actually going to get a
reference this time to our animators.
So similar to how we
got a reference to our rigid
body, we're going to get a
reference to our animators.
So we'll also make
this private because we
don't need to find this
outside of our class.
It'll be of type
animator, not animation,
and we'll just call this player,
and for now, for player animation.
Now just like our rigid
body, we actually need
to get the actual
component on our object.
So player anim is set to our get component,
and what component are we getting?
Our animator, and then make sure to
call the method and close your statement.
Now in our update
function is actually where
we want this animation
to happen, but what
animation exactly are
we trying to make happen?
Well, let's see.
In Unity, if we go to
our animator, and we
find our player animator,
now if we take a look
at our layers again, you can see that we
have all of our different layers, and we want
our player to jump, so
we'll go to our jumping layer.
And we're going to center
all of our animation states.
Now we have one that goes
from run to running jump.
Now how do we get there?
Interesting.
So you can see, to get from run, under our
conditions, there's something called a jump
trig.
So let's see if in our
parameters, so we do
have something called a jump
trig that we would be able to use.
Now if we follow the
naming of all of these
different variables, so
you can see we have speed
underscore F, so that must be a float, and
under animation int, so that's an integer,
their whole numbers,
under our static B,
crouch B, so since they're check
boxes, they're probably booleans.
So I think our jump
trig is probably actually
a trigger that you could think very
similarly like the triggers on our colliders.
So in our player controller
script, so we have
this place where we
make this jump actually
happen, so let's see,
so if we use our player
animator, let's take
a look at some of the
methods, that's super
convenient, dot set triggers,
set the value of the
given trigger parameter,
and it's got an overload.
Let's see, that seems like something that
we want to use, so we'll use set trigger.
That way we can use our jump trig,
let's see, maybe what's the other option?
Oh, I can just use the name.
So if we set this to be, I believe it was
spelled like so, now this set trigger method
should activate our jump trigger when we
press the space bars inside or if statement.
Well, let's give it a try,
let's see what happens.
So if we play our game
and we jump, oh my
gosh, that was a little
weird, but we have the
jumping animation,
that's cool, it kind of
looks like Superman
or something, superhero.
All right, so to get started activating these
animations, what we're going to do is in
our player controller class, make sure that
you add your own animator variable and then
in the start method,
make sure that you assign
your animator variable
to the animator component
and then in our update
method, where the player
actually jumps, just make sure to
set the trigger for our jump animation.
Now it's your turn.